# HEBER BERMUDEZ

## Statistician

hebermudezg@unal.edu.co  $\cdot (+57)3115604078$ 

https://hebermudezg.com/

#### PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I am an Statistician with experience collecting, analyzing, interpreting, and presenting quantitative information, providing insight and recommendations on policies and strategies. I have worked in data visualization for business intelligence, written reports, development and implementation of predictive models, database management and software development. I possess strong IT and analytical skills, as well as the interpersonal and communication skills to share findings with colleagues and clients. I apply statistical theories and methods to solve practical problems in a range of sectors, including; engineering, science, education, the environment, health, transportation, software companies, among others.

#### **EDUCATION**

# National University of Colombia

2015-2021

Undergraduate in Statistics.

Overall GPA: 4.1/5.0

SENA 2013-2015

Technologist in industrial production managemen.

SENA 2010-2012

Software development technician.

## **EXPERIENCE**

# Infection and Cancer Research Group

Dec 2020 - Jul 2021

Epidemiological data analysis, Antioquia University.

• I provided support from my knowledge and experience in the statistical analysis of epidemiological data for research projects and publications in scientific journals, achieving the identification of risk profiles of breast cancer in Latin American women considering hormonal and reproductive factors.

#### Unalytics, data science seedbed

Jan 2019 - Jun 2020

Assistant student, National University of Colombia.

- I created and directed the seedbed where I taught theoretical and practical skills in the area of data science, data analysis and artificial intelligence, where I managed together with my team to develop various products and exhibit them in competitions, conferences and colloquia. See more: https://unalyticsteam.github.io/unalytics/
- Participation in scientific dissemination projects..

Biosuplies SAS Jan 2014 - Feb 2015

Documentation and quality control assistant, Biosuplies SAS

- I created forms and process manuals as well as software programs to automate administrative tasks such as inventory maintenance and quality control.
- I developed a form to reduce the times of prescription of magisterial medicines.

### AWARDS AND RECOGNITIONS

# Student Representative (2019)

Student representative of the Conflict Resolution and Disciplinary Aspects Committee of the Faculty of Sciences of the National University of Colombia elected by vote.

# Founder of Unalytics - data science seedbed (2019)

Founder of the analytical and data science seedbed attached to the school of statistics of the National University of Colombia as a pedagogical strategy.

# Best degree project (2011)

Technical College of the City of Ibagué (Highschool) - Best degree project related to software programming and website design.

#### TECHNICAL STRENGTHS

**Programming** R, Python, Java, Visual Basic, React Native.

Databases SQL.

Data Visualization, BI Power BI, Tableau.

Machine Learning, AI Pandas, Numpy, Scikit-learn, Tidyverse, Knime

Website design HTML and CSS.

Typesetting Document Latex.

# ACADEMIC ACTIVITIES

## XIII National statistics colloquium

2021

Attendant, National University of Colombia.

# XII National statistics colloquium

2019

Sepaker: Machine learning for text analysis, National University of Colombia.

#### XXIX International statistical symposium

2019

Speaker: Text mining to study some terminologies about data science in Colombia, Northern University.

DATATON BC 2019

Data science and artificial intelligence challenge, Bancolombia bank.

Modeling of credit risk from the digital trace. We were top 20% Kaggle Challenge.

DATATON BC 2018

Data science and artificial intelligence challenge, Bancolombia bank.

Text mining to identify expenses by categories.

#### CERTIFICATIONS, MOOCS

#### Introduction to data science

Coursera, Autonomous University of Mexico

## Deep learning

Coursera, Deeplearning.ai

#### SQL for Data science

Coursera, DAVIS University

#### LANGUAGES

English Intermediate.

Spanish Native.